ADAPTED FROM THE BLOSSOMING LOVE
BY SUI YU ER AN ON ICEREAD.COM
I can help you go back in time
and change the course of that girl's life
before she dies.
You can think of a time
and place in the past
that you want to go back to.
I will send you back
with the samsara mirror.
If the Immortals Array hadn't been broken,
it wouldn't have had to be rebuilt,
and in the end, she wouldn't have died.
I will go back to before
the Immortals Array was broken
and stop He Xianwo.
This is the samsara mirror.
Only your spirit can enter
and go back to you in the past.
Once out of your body,
the spirit is unprotected
and will be crushed by the mill of time.
It can be smashed.
Remember,
do not try to change the fate of others
or make your existence known to anyone,
or you will not be able to pay the price,
and countless others
will fall victims to this fate.
The worst that can happen
is that the whole world
will twist and fall apart.
All gone.
I know.
Is he the one I've been waiting for?
-Xuechen.
-Senior.
-Xie Xuechen.
-Xuechen.
-Senior.
Xie Xuechen.
Why
are you staring at me like that?
Xuanling.
I won't put you in any more danger.
I don't want to lose you again.
Xie Xuechen. What's wrong with you?
What happened?
He Xianwo is the Master
of the Decaying Immortal Pavilion.
He's going to the Dark Abyss
to break the Immortals Array.
What? How do you know that?
I don't have time to explain.
I must be transported immediately.
Should I call you Master He
or the Master
of the Decaying Immortal Pavilion?
If I remember correctly,
you've only seen my face once.
Did I give it away,
or
did someone tell you?
Your spirit is calm and stable,
so you are by no means a youth.
There are many cultivators in the world,
but except for the disguise technique,
you're the only one who can do
shapeshift and skin-changing.
-Who are you?
-You not only don't answer my questions
but also want to know something from me.
It doesn't matter.
Whether you answer or not,
I'm going to kill you today.
Coincidentally,
I have the same intention.
You've gotten so much stronger
in a short time.
It's impressive.
I'm kind of hoping he'll succeed
because it'll prove
he's the one I'm waiting for.
Just give me a little more time.
Just a little.
Why now?
It could have been changed.
It failed after all.
Did I succeed?
Unfortunately, reality didn't change,
and the person you love
didn't come back to life.
It could have been changed.
Just a little.
Just give me a little more time,
and I can stop He Xianwo.
Since you promised
to help me return to the past
and change her fate,
why did you suddenly pull me back
to reality at that critical moment?
You misunderstood me.
I didn't bring you back
to reality on purpose.
Time and space are unstable,
so the time you can stay there is limited.
Once the time is up,
you will be forced to return to reality.
Then, how long can I stay in the past?
One day at most.
Only one day?
One day is the limit.
I can endure any amount of pain
as long as I can save her.
The damage to the spirit is irreversible.
Each time you pass through
the Samsara Mirror,
your spirit is weaker than the last,
until it is destroyed.
Even so, will you continue to try?
Yes.
Since your mind is made up,
I will help you again.
Think carefully.
Which point in time
do you want to return to this time?
I've thought about it.
It's only one night.
I have to take Ling out of the Dark Abyss
within that one night.
As long as she is no longer
the Saintess of the Dark Abyss,
she can live peacefully
and will not have to be involved
in what happened later.
At this point,
I was still in seclusion in Snow Cliff,
so I couldn't be seen
coming down the mountain.
Luckily, I learned how to make
an Anti-illusion Hairpin from Ling
and was able to conceal my appearance.
It's been a long time since I've had
one of the Spirit Clan this fresh.
Get lost.
Stupid Dark Clan.
Mister put his life
on the line to save me,
so I must not die here like this.
Don't be afraid, girl.
I'm not your enemy.
You look pathetic,
but you've done so well
that you've survived the hunt
from so many men of the Dark Clan.
You saw me being hunted but didn't help,
so you're not my friend at least.
I made a bet with Ignorance Demon
on which of the group of the Spirit Clan
people His Grace brought back
would survive to the end.
I told him it would be you,
but he didn't believe me.
Now,
while all the other
of the Spirit Clan are dead,
you're the only one who survived.
You're the toughest of them all,
and that's why I admire you.
So,
what gives you
such a strong desire to live?
Countless money
or endless delicacies
or a luxurious wonderland
or supreme power?
I don't care about any of those things.
And what is there
in this world for you to hold on to?
I'm not holding on to this world.
I just don't allow myself
to die like this.
Interesting. Why is that?
None of your business.
Do you find
the Dark Clan so evil and disgusting
that you don't even want to talk to me?
Isn't it true?
You act on your desires and have no sense.
You should be grateful.
Because the Dark Clan is like that,
you have a chance to live
in the Dark Abyss.
The people of the Dark Clan,
whose desires are most obvious,
are the easiest to exploit.
In fact, so are the Humans.
You should not despise desire
but utilize it.
That way, you can manipulate
the Dark Clan and even hearts.
I don't want to be like you.
To survive evil,
you must first become evil.
Only by becoming the ultimate evil
can you fight evil.
Remember that?
Think about it.
Why did you come to the Dark Abyss,
and why are you alive?
Above all,
you have to know what you want
and get what you want.
You're right.
Now,
do I look like a villain?
I'm sure we'll meet again.
I finally found it.
Why would anyone set a trap like this
on their doorstep?
It's a good thing
I'm wearing the Anti-illusion Hairpin.
You shameless Dark Clan people.
You see me as a newcomer.
You guys come to harass me
from time to time.
Luckily, I set the trap in advance.
I was just passing through.
-Who'd believe you?
-Why would I lie to you?
I saw the Xuanling Tree in bloom
when I was passing by,
so I was curious and got closer,
but I didn't expect
to fall into your trap.
You seem to have some aesthetic.
So,
there's a lot of bullying
going on in the Dark Clan?
Of course.
There are no good guys
in the Dark Clan like you,
especially that Ignorance Demon guy.
He's always giving me trouble
and making me uncomfortable.
After I have developed
the most powerful demonic power
and defeated the Dark Clan,
I will make him kneel down
and call me King.
I can't let her go on like this,
or she'll be on her set trajectory again.
Do you want to learn
the great demonic power?
I can teach you.
You?
You even hit my traps,
so how can you teach me?
TWILIGHT SPIRIT PAVILION
How about this? Amazing?
That's good, bro.
I'll give you a pass.
Come on, bro,
-Let's go inside and talk.
-Be gentle.
Be gentle.
I've only seen her being cocky
in front of the Dark Clan,
but I didn't realize
she was so down on her luck
when she first came to the Dark Abyss.
She said
she had demonic patterns
on her face as a child,
but I didn't see them.
Come on, bro. Have some tea.
What's your amazing power?
Teach me.
I'm going to be more like
the Dark Clan than themselves.
Being like the Dark Clan
is not a good thing.
Why not?
Desire Demon said that joining the ranks
of evil and becoming more than evil
would be one step closer
to destroying the Humans.
Why do you hate the Humans so much?
Don't be blinded by hate
or give up on yourself.
You know what?
There are many bad people in this world,
but there are also
good people, like Mister.
If he were still around,
he'd want you to live simply and happily,
like a normal person.
How do you know Mister?
Stop using those crooked abilities
to read my mind.
I just don't want you to force yourself
to be someone else.
I'm not.
I just want to be
as strong as the Dark Clan.
No.
I want to be stronger
than all the Dark Clans,
and you,
as a Dark Clan,
are so un-Dark-Clan.
If I say I'm not the Dark Clan,
will you come with me?
I would take you to a place
where you could live out your life
without strife or pain.
No.
I want revenge for Mister.
I can only get stronger
if I stay in the Dark Abyss.
Is Mister that important to you?
Do you want to stay in the Dark Abyss,
even though you will
be bullied by the Dark Clan,
live in pain and fear,
and even lose your life?
To me,
Mister is the most important person.
I will suffer
and do anything
for him.
Time is running out.
-Come with me.
-What are you doing?
-You have to get out of here.
-Let go. I've said it. I'm not leaving.
This is a flare from the Dark Abyss.
Once it's fired,
the entire Dark Abyss will go on alert,
and Sang Qi will immediately
bring the Dark Clan after you.
When the time comes,
you will not be able to leave.
I don't care who you are
or what your intentions are,
and I won't expose you,
-but you must leave my house immediately.
-Ling.
If you don't leave, I will fire it.
It will be dawn in the human realm.
I have to get back
to Snow City before then,
or all will be in chaos.
Go.
Now.
TWILIGHT SPIRIT PAVILION
This time,
I didn't quite get the timing right,
but luckily, my spirit was still alive,
so I still had a chance.
I've been in seclusion
in Snow Cliff for a long time now.
The Swirling Snow Pavilion
had been unused,
so who would be in my place
in the middle of the night?
SWIRLING SNOW PAVILION
I always thought
that after what happened
in Moonlight Heights,
my father was disappointed in me
and didn't want to see me anymore.
He was so cold that day
when he asked me to leave the mountain,
but why?
If Leader Xie were still around,
he would have wanted to say to you,
"Xuechen,
I've been treating you harshly
for so many years,
but I've always known
how difficult it was for you."
He will never hand over
the Snow City Jade Token even if he dies.
Remember,
do not try to change the fate of others
or make your existence known to anyone,
or you will not be able to pay the price,
and countless others
will fall victims to this fate.
The worst that can happen
is that the whole world
will twist and fall apart.
All gone.
If there is a day in the future
when my life and the human world
are on opposite sides of the fence,
you don't have to worry
and must firmly choose the latter.
Don't be blinded by hate
or give up on yourself.
You know what?
There are many bad people in this world,
but there are also
good people like Mister.
If he were still around,
he'd want you to live simply and happily,
like a normal person.
If it were Mister,
what would he want me to do?
TWILIGHT SPIRIT PAVILION
Time's up.
Ling.
I'm back.
You're finally awake.
It's good to see you
again.
Ling.
This time,
we'll never be apart again.
OK.
Now, the war
between man and spirit is over,
and the Immortals Array has been repaired.
The world is at peace.
You promised me you'd take me
to the human world.
Don't go back on your word.
Take me there now, okay?
Okay.
Ling.
Mu Xuanling.
Xuanling.
You're awake.
You're very weak now. Don't push yourself.
How is she?
The world remains unchanged.
I'm confused
about one thing.
Ling said
she had large demonic patterns
on her face when she was young,
but I didn't see
any demonic patterns on her face.
Why?
I can't give you an answer.
If you want to know the cause and effect,
you need to find out for yourself.
Let me try again.
Your spirit is severely damaged.
If you force yourself
to time travel again,
you may not make it back.
Even if it's the last hope,
I have to try.
She's still waiting for me.
MOONLIGHT HEIGHTS
Don't be lazy.
Listen up.
Tonight is the birthday party
for the Master's daughter.
Be careful and work hard.
And don't disturb the guests
in the front yard.
Bunch of humble slaves.
The water tank isn't full yet.
Who's in charge here?
It's Ling.
It's freezing these days,
and the river is frozen,
so she has to break the ice to get water.
Stop the bullshit.
Oh my God. You're slacking off again.
What time is it?
The tanks in the yard aren't full yet.
You can spill even these tanks.
You seem to be sneaking around on purpose.
Sir.
I've been picking water all night
and haven't been able to eat,
so I don't have the strength.
Still arguing?
The spirit slave never lacks strength.
I met you, an abandoned baby,
under the tree
and fed you so you could grow up,
but how dare you cheat and be ungrateful?
I think you, a lowly spirit slave,
need to be punished.
Don't be afraid.
Are you feeling cold?
I'm a spirit slave,
and the head says
spirit slaves don't get cold.
Do you feel better?
Who are you?
How dare you hit me? Do you know who I am?
I'm sorry. It's my fault.
This man deserves to die,
but I came here to take Ling away before
Sang Qi's bloodshed in Moonlight Heights
so that she can get rid
of her spirit slave status
and live well.
Killing someone who doesn't matter
will only give me a momentary relief,
but it could end badly.
Spare me.
Get lost.
Will you come with me?
Are you our honored guest?
I'm a spirit slave,
so I'll obey the head.
You're not a spirit slave.
Haven't you eaten yet?
I can't eat until I've filled
all the water tanks in the yard.
I'll take you to a meal.
QIN'S RESTAURANT AND BAR
Good snacks.
Please come again.
-Come inside!
-Best rouge in town!
BRIGHT MOON INN
Don't ever say it doesn't hurt again.
I won't let you get hurt again.
LIQUOR
Here you go, sir.
Thank you.
Enjoy.
There are so many dishes here,
but why do you only have congee?
Congee fills me up.
I used to drink congee all the time.
The dim sum tastes like this.
It's delicious.
It's too inconvenient for you
to eat with your mask on.
Take it off.
No.
I have demonic patterns on my face.
It's ugly. It'll scare you.
It won't.
I knew you'd be beautiful
when I saw your eyes.
So, this is the pattern
from the Chaos Power,
but why would he suddenly disappear?
Does that scare you?
No.
Your demonic patterns are beautiful.
No wonder you didn't want
anyone to see it.
Come on.
This snack is really good.
Why are you being so nice to me?
Do you want me to do something?
You don't have to do anything.
I just want you to be happy.
So, are you
my long-lost father?
Do you hope so?
If so,
that's fine.
Why?
In that case,
you'd take me with you.
You abandoned me for so many years,
so you have to make it up to me.
How do you want me to make it up to you?
I want to wear nice clothes,
eat good food,
live in a big house,
and sleep four hours a day.
Okay. I promise you.
I'll take you dress shopping later,
-okay?
-Okay, Father.
Don't call me Father.
You didn't tell me your name,
so what should I call you?
If she knows my name,
we'll be involved again in the future.
You've already done too much for me,
so I don't want to see you
sacrifice yourself for me again.
I just want you to live a good life,
even if it's no longer me you love.
Anyway, no calling me Father.
Then,
can I call you Mister?
What did you say?
Mister.
It's never me
you're hung up on.
He's my Mister.
He gave me my life.
Mister.
Do you like dim sum so much?
When I was in the human world,
the first thing Mister took me to eat
was dim sum.
So, that's how it is.
The Mister she mentioned
over and over again was me.
All the clues have been there
and obvious for a long time,
but I didn't realize it until now.
What's wrong?
Does it bother you
that I called you Mister?
-No.
-So,
can I call you Mister?
Okay.
Mister.
Ling.
Mister. Thank you for taking me
to the medical center for treatment
and buying me new clothes.
The clothes are nice. I like it.
I'm glad you like it.
Today is the Timekeeper Festival.
They say it's for the Chaos Pearl.
They say that 6,000 years ago,
the Immortal Alliance
used the power of the Chaos Pearl
to build the Immortals Array
to keep the human realm
safe from the Dark Clan.
But in fact,
the Humans never asked
the Chaos Pearl what she wanted
or if she was willing to be sacrificed.
Isn't the Chaos Pearl a pearl?
Does it talk?
Mister. What's wrong with you?
Are you sad?
As long as you're happy,
I'm not sad.
If only we could watch fireworks together
like this at future Timekeeper Festivals.
-This is amazing.
-Indeed.
I'm just saying.
It's okay if we don't
get a chance like this.
The head doesn't allow us
to celebrate the Humans' festival.
Because we're spirit slaves.
No. I'll take you away.
Every Timekeeper Festival from now on,
you'll be able to see the fireworks.
Really?
Thank you.
Ling.
I'm sorry.
Taking you away
and staying with you are different.
If you stay with Xie Xuechen,
there will still be unknown risks.
I will take you away,
but in the future,
you must be on your own,
forget about me,
and live well.
I'd love to take you now,
but the Spirit Lock on your foot
restricts your range of motion,
so if we force our way out,
it will jeopardize your life.
It's only been one day,
but I'm very happy,
so, Mister, you don't have to lie to me.
Even if you really can't take me with you,
I won't blame you.
I'm not lying to you.
I really want to take you away…
MOONLIGHT HEIGHTS
…so I'm going to go to Mr. Gao
and ask him to unlock
the Spirit Lock for you.
Really?
But Mr. Gao
is in the Spiritual Form stage,
very powerful.
If you can't, don't push yourself.
Don't worry.
I'll get you out of here.
Master. Mr. Xie from Snow City
wants to see you.
Xie Xuechen?
Why is he here all of a sudden?
-Let him in.
-Yes, sir.
I envy her.
-Her brand birthday party every year.
-Get to work.
But we have to work hard every time.
We work from morning
till night for this day.
That's enough.
We are the Spirit Clan
who are born inferior.
At least we don't starve
in Moonlight Heights.
Sang Qi bloodied
Moonlight Heights that year
on Gao Qiumin's birthday.
So, it's tonight?
Sang Qi has been planning
this battle for years,
so stopping him is almost impossible.
What happened to Feng Xiang
is still fresh in my mind,
and the samsara mirror
has repeatedly told me
not to change the trajectory of the past.
As long as I can take Ling away
before it happens
and prevent her from
being caught by Sang Qi,
I will have achieved
the purpose of my trip.
This man has done so many dirty deeds
and is very cunning,
so I have to be careful in front of him
and not let him find out
that Ling is the Chaos Pearl.